# **Sangram Chavan**

# Principal Software Engineer | Full-Stack Web Engineer

With over 10+ years experience, I am passionate engineer with demonstrated history of working in SaaS based product companies. Efficient and skilled architect with a diverse knowledge of technologies. I have been a full-stack web engineer who garnered a multitude of experiences in the field of server-side and front-end programming. I am familiar with Infrastructure & DevOps tools such as AWS Cloud, CI/CD Tools, Jenkins and Docker.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Freelance Consultant, Pune

Since February 2018

I solve various kinds of technical problems as an independent consultant.

- Code Refactoring, Performance Profiling, Database Tuning
- Frontend development
- Consult technological strategy for startups

# **Druva Data Solution Pvt. Ltd.**, Pune, India — Principal Software Engineer

September 2015 – September 2017

As a Principal Engineer I have been -

- Leading a frontend development team for inSync Product.
- Work with Product Managers & other development team to support and maintain existing production code in the field and develop and deliver new enhancements and products.
- Liaise with environment specialists to ensure smooth deployments to production.
- Provide feedback to the engagement manager's on the quality of team.
- Ensure the team keeps necessary architectural & technical design documents up to date.
- Keep the product manager's & support engineer's informed and engaged in the technical side of the project.
- Assign tasks to team members taking into account their strengths, weaknesses and capabilities.
- Provide technical guidance to engineers on their respective development tasks and pitch in with individual contribution.
- Mentor team members towards good design, coding and testing practices.
- Work with other developers on the Druva development team on the implementation of common frameworks and solutions.
- Have strong sense of ownership and work with the product management team to understand requirements, refine them based on technical feasibility and drive the team to deliver them.
- Stay up-to-date on web technologies.

# **CONTACT**

#### Address:

B-906, Samruddhi Lakeshore SNo. 62/11B Jambhulwadi Road, Ambegaon (Kh), Pune, MH India - 411046

**Tel:** +91-9860328574

Mail: <a href="mailto:schavan@outlook.com">schavan@outlook.com</a> Skype: live:sangram.chavan

#### **TECHNOLOGY EXPERIENCE**

- Microsoft .Net (8 years)
- Python (2 years)
- ASP.NET, JavaScript, jQuery (7 years)
- ReactJS, AngularJS (3 years)
- WCF & Windows Services (8 years)
- AWS (3 years)
- Docker (3 years)
- SQL (5 years)
- GoLang (Beginner)

#### **DEVELOPMENT SKILLS**

#### Frameworks & Languages:

C#, Python, TypeScript, JavaScript, Microsoft .NET Stack

#### Server Side Programming:

ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, .NET Core, Entity Framework, Web Services, WCF, WF, CherryPy, NodeJs, GoLang (Beginner)

#### Client Side Programming:

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, BackboneJS, KnockoutJS, AngularJS, ReactJS.

# Tavisca Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Pune, India — Technical Lead

December 2008 - September 2015

As a Technical Lead I have been

- Facilitating technical communication with other teams.
- Have a clear understanding of the deployment architecture & build pipeline
- Understand how all parts of the system work together
- Ensure we have a release / branching strategy in place
- Ensure adherence to standards of technical best practices.
- Ensure there is a technical vision for the team
- Keep an eye on the long term consequences of architectural choices, and remind others when necessary
- Actively seek to remove knowledge silos within the team

# Nihilent Technology Pvt. Ltd., Pune, India — Software Engineer

September 2007 - December 2008

As a software engineer I have been

- Creating a high level design using core design principles.
- Creating detailed design documents for the rest of the development team
- Do development using C#, ASP.NET, JavaScript, Enterprise Application Block, SQL Server
- Develop of unit test suite.
- Coordinating the UAT and production deployment and production support issues.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Sunbeam Institute Of Technology**, Pune — *PG-DAC*

February 2007 - August 2007

Completed 6 months full time Post Graduate Diploma in Advanced Computing course with A grade.

# **Savitribai Phule Pune University,** Pune — Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science)

July 2002 - July 2006

Completed this degree from College of Engineering, Malegaon, Baramati.

I successful completed all the credits without any fallout and got distinction.

# **Kisan Veer Mahavidyalaya,** Wai — Higher Secondary School

July 2001 - July 2002

Completed Higher Secondary School without any fallout & got First Class.

# St. Thomas High School, Wai — Secondary School

July 2000 - July 2001

Completed Higher Secondary School without any fallout & got First Class.

#### Testing:

XUnit, MSTest, Coded UI Test, MS Fakes, Mog, Jasmine, QUnit.

## Continuous Integration:

Jenkins, Cruise Control .Net, GitLab Pipelines

# Deployment & Tools:

Docker, IIS, Redis, ELK-Stack

#### Cloud:

Amazon Web Services

#### **ALM Tools:**

Mingle, Jira, TFS.

#### Methodologies:

Agile Methodology (Scrum), Pair programming, TDD, OOP.

#### **Source Control:**

Subversion, Visual SourceSafe, TFS, GIT.

#### Databases:

MS SQL Server, MySql, NoSQL

#### **SOCIAL**

# LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sangram-chavan/

#### Twitter:

https://twitter.com/sangram\_tw eets

#### StackOverflow:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/1790376/sangram

## GitHub:

https://github.com/sangram-ch avan

## **LANGUAGES**

**English:** Professional Proficiency

**Hindi:** *Professional Proficiency* 

Marathi: Native or Bilingual

Proficiency

#### **inSync** — Endpoint backup solution (<a href="https://www.druva.com/products/insync/">https://www.druva.com/products/insync/</a>)

inSync provides a unified data protection and information governance solution that delivers a single pane of glass for viewing and managing dispersed data across endpoints and cloud applications - facilitating business continuity while not impacting employee productivity.

# Oski — Uniformed Travel API Cloud Platform (<a href="http://docs.oski.io/one-connect">http://docs.oski.io/one-connect</a>)

Booking Engines or the Travel API is the backbone for all travel applications built by Tavisca, Engines cater to the actual search, pricing & booking for all products, solely responsible for connecting to suppliers, gathering results, applying mark-ups along with business logic. Engines are also the key component in ensuring the shortest time to market and must ensure quick customization support.

Oski is an initiative to re-engineer the Booking Engines into a more performant, customizable & configurable solution.

#### **Templar**— *White label website development software*

(https://www.tavisca.com/travel-technology-software/white-label-website-builder-templar/)

Templar is a widgetized UI framework with complete travel and back-office widgets available out of the box, which can be customized and extended without reinventing the wheel. Creating a new brand, theme and look and feel is now a creative designer's work. This promises significant reduction in cost and time to market.

# **Synchron**— *Mid-office* synchronization software

(https://www.tavisca.com/travel-technology-software/automated-ticketing-notification-synchron/)

Synchron downloads and monitors PNRs from GDS and Queues to automatically identify the business workflow efficiency. It sends out notifications to customers for ticketing, schedule change, cancellation and any post booking event which needs customers' attention.

## **Innventia** — *Inventory management system*

(https://www.tavisca.com/travel-technology-software/inventory-management-system-innventia/)

A comprehensive travel inventory management system which enables travel businesses to manage their inventory, operations and selectively distribute their niche content to a wider audience, at will. Innventia is an integrated platform with ability to manage rates and inventory for hotel, car and activity. Powered by a time tested booking platform, Innventia connects suppliers to travel agents worldwide, facilitating better ROI, access to niche inventory around the world and global markets.

#### **New Lamat Tool** — *Strategy execution and performance management software* (*Nihilent Product*)

Lamat is a comprehensive performance management tool that uses the Balanced Scorecard concept for the purpose of performance measurement. Lamat creates a foundation for collaboration by providing everyone in the organization with a holistic view of the company's strategies and helping them understand how their role impacts the overall performance of the organization.

# **Goals Tracker v2** — Performance monitoring tool (Nihilent's Client Project)

Goal Tracker System is a performance monitoring system that helps an organization to monitor the performance entities like measures and its goals, subgoals. It is web-based system, which has three modules Administration Module, Manager Module and Super User Module.